The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Eighteenth Episode
The Magic Mirror
Fantastic!
The best soup in the world!
It has such a delicious scent
that it makes your mouth water!
Come in!
Good morning, Princess Bella!
I have prepared an excellent soup for you.
I recommend you eat it.
I don't want to eat. You know that
I eat one grain of rice a day.
But how can you sustain yourself
on a grain of rice?!
I told you
that I don't want to eat
I must be careful
not to ruin my figure.
Do you want to make me fat?
No, no... I am so sorry, Your Highness
My dear magic mirror,
please, tell me:
who is the most beautiful in all creation?
Listen, my dear Bella.
If you want to know, I will tell you.
Of the universe, of course, I do not know,
but of this country
you are the star.
Therefore, gentle and royal Highness,
consider yourself satisfied
with your beauty.
Magnificent! I am sure that a woman
more beautiful than me cannot exist!
I want to make sure of it by traveling through
all the regions of the world.
There it is! I'm almost right over it!
Got it!
It's really a nice little hare!
Go! I saw it! There
it is! Now I'll catch it!
And with this one, that
makes 11 hares! Not bad, eh?
Come on, Opale!
In mid-air! Like that!
With these, I've caught 12!
What bad luck!
I've found more! Magnificent!
Three in one go!
Did you get hurt?
Actually, I was better
off before, Your Highness.
See, Grand Duke? Did you
think I would end up defeated?
When it comes to skill
and dexterity, I'm no sissy!
What do you say? Actually, I proposed it to you
because it's a very manly game.
So, if I won, it means
that I'm very manly, right?
- Answer! - So it would seem,
by all accounts.
If he still isn't convinced, I'll have to
give him another demonstration.
But what kind?
Fantastic!
How big this carriage is!
It even has an upper level
and looks very luxurious!
Gorgeous!
Look, there are stairs too!
Incredible! It's divided
into rooms, like a house!
Nothing is missing!
There's even a kitchen!
I wonder who the lucky person is who lives
in a carriage like this...!
I want to take a look
There's no one here...
Incredible!
A real bedroom!
There's also a mirror.
What?! What a strange mirror.
I wonder why it doesn't reflect
one's figure properly...!
I'd like to look at myself in it.
Now it has become normal.
Make essences
with the flowers you have gathered.
As you wish.
- There's someone!
- Thief!
- No, wait! I'm not a thief!
Then who are you?
- I'm sorry to have frightened you, but I...
- What is it, Your Highness?
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
- Oh, no!
- You'll have to deal with me!
- Just let me catch you and...
- There's a misunderstanding! Wait!
He managed to escape!
That scoundrel got you
dirty, but now I'll clean you up.
Listen, my dear mirror,
my magic mirror!
Please, tell me:
who is the most beautiful in creation?
My dear Beauty,
if you wish, I will tell you.
Of the world I do not know, but of this
place you are no longer the star.
Accept my invitation:
resign yourself to fate,
for nearby
is one more beautiful than you.
Do you mean that in this country
there is one more beautiful than me?!
My Princess, it is true.
What I assert this morning...
...you will see of the realm
in the next castle.
Now you will be informed of a beauty that
is enclosed upon all this earth.
Sapphire she is named.
I feel like dying at the thought
of no longer being the most beautiful!
My little Sapphire
What are you doing, my daughter?
Good! Better that indiscreet
ears do not hear...
- that I call you like a little girl.
- Yes, mother.
Oh, what tenderness!
How I wish you could grow up
as a girl,
without being forced
to hide your identity
..because of our laws!
Our laws are the most precious
possession we have.
If we do not observe them,
the people will not forgive us
Oh, my little Sapphire!
- What do you desire?
- I am looking for a certain Sapphire.
- Do you know who she is?
- Yes, Sapphire is the King's daughter.
She lives in the nearby castle
So it is true
that there is this girl!
- Let's run to the castle!
- Right away, Princess!
No! No, I was wrong!
Sapphire is a boy!
He's a strong and brave
boy! He is not a girl!
What?! Are you sure
that Sapphire is a girl?
Yes, I am sure of it! My
magic mirror never lies...
...and it claims exactly that. It also
said that she is more beautiful than me.
Do you mean you have
a magic mirror?!
But then it is truly a stroke of luck!
It is good fortune that
sends you here to us!
Now I would like to see
Sapphire. I must verify...
...if the mirror is right, if she is
really more beautiful than me.
Yes, of course, I understand!
Don't worry, Your Highness.
I will call her for you shortly
- What are you waiting for?
- Things are getting interesting
because there is a secret involved
that finally...
...through you
it will be possible to reveal!
Let's get a little practice,
Nylon!
- But you are the thief from yesterday!
- Yeah!
Sapphire?!
I can beat you even with this!
Come on!
You know, I'm out of practice!
Step forward!
You are as weak as a girl!
Well?
Do you admit your defeat?
Defeat? No...
You say no?
Welcome to my castle,
Princess.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I am Prince Sapphire.
I must tell you that I have never seen
a girl more beautiful than you.
You are enchanting!
Truly very beautiful!
Thank you, Your Highness.
But are you really a boy?
Why do you doubt it? I have even
admired your beauty!
And soon,
I'll even grow a mustache
Good heavens,
I prefer not to look at you!
Now I believe you.
Indeed, I hope you won't be offended,
if I tell you that I find you
rather ugly.
You teased me by saying
that Sapphire was more beautiful than me.
Now be serious and tell me:
who is the most beautiful?
The answer is that:
Sapphire is the most beautiful.
But Sapphire is a boy! Do you want
to keep teasing me?
What seems to be, is not.
Believe what you wish.
It doesn't seem so at all,
but Sapphire is a maiden.
Go to hell!
We would be honored if you
stayed a little longer in Silverland.
I accept, because I have to
settle a matter close to my heart.
May I know what it is about?
Well, you see... I have to convince
the mirror that I am the most beautiful.
Of course, I understand you!
Then allow me to help you.
...and to offer you
hospitality in my nearby castle.
No, thank you, Baron.
Allow me to take you to the
best inn in the entire realm!
I'd rather not. I prefer to
reside in the palace of the mirror,
...that Chop will build for me.
- I'll build it right away, Your Highness.
But Your Highness, surely you don't
want to have a palace built for you?!
Do you think that I
can stay in an inn?
As soon as it's done, come to
my palace. I will receive you there.
I'm afraid I've given
myself away, Sapphire.
Now be careful, because
Bella might discover your secret.
You know, now you should
behave more manly than usual.
Yeah, but in what way
can I seem more manly?
Let me think a bit
about this problem.
I've got it! You look more
manly when you fight!
When I fight, you say?
Hey, Sapphire! She's coming!
Nothing beats a good
glass of beer with friends!
And now it's your turn!
Come on, you blockheads! Bring it on!
Fight! Bella is watching!
Go get 'em, Sapphire!
Show them your manly spirit!
- That Prince doesn't seem like a girl.
- He doesn't, but...
Maybe it's a pity, so big...
Maybe this one!
Or this one! I changed my mind!
- What a struggle!
- Well done, Sapphire!
Wonderful, Prince Sapphire!
If I had known
that you were watching,
I would have fought
more bravely.
Accept the invitation
to come to my palace.
- I will be very happy to receive you.
- In your palace?!
Yes! It will be called
'Mirror Palace".
Mirror Palace?!
A truly strange name.
But, you know,
it hasn't been built yet.
What? You want to build yourself a palace?
Yes, it will be built in five
minutes. Please, come!
Sounds interesting!
I accept your invitation.
Be careful,
it could be a trap
Excuse me, I remembered that I have to
return to the castle to study.
Don't tell me you study.
Studying is certainly not
for brave people.
Well, then, if you think so,
it means I won't study.
- Then remember that I'm waiting for you.
- Yes.
- I want it to be built here.
- Yes, Princess.
It's already built.
You can enter.
I can't understand
how it was possible.
...to build it so quickly.
Good heavens, a
boy who is afraid!
Really, I'm not afraid!
Wait for me in the
back room, please.
All right!
Now we'll see! If it's a
girl, she will faint from fear.
It's only a mirror.
I found him passed out
in front of the multi-mirror.
Tell the maids to dress Sapphire
..in a woman's dress
and put makeup on him.
As soon as she is ready, I will compare
myself with her to see who is the most beautiful.
It will all be done, Your Highness.
We have finished putting makeup on her!
How beautiful! I am shocked!
She is indeed very beautiful!
Mirror, my mirror,
tell me once again:
who is more beautiful? Sapphire or I?
Satisfaction is not granted to you,
the answer is ever the same.
Even if over seas and mountains
you have traveled satisfied,
the illusion that your supremacy
over the world does not fade..
...gives way to despair
for a dream that is now dead.
Of the realm, the most beautiful
is Sapphire, always her.
- My loyal servant..
- Yes, Your Highness?
- Sapphire must no longer live.
- As you wish, Your Highness.
Anyone who is more beautiful than me
must be punished.
It shall be done.
Wait!
I order you to kill Sapphire
at all costs!
Away, Opal!
First let's test this weapon.
Perfect!
And now...
I must hurry!
This time you won't escape me!
There it is!
That mirror on the wall..!
It's over for you!
I will turn this weapon
against them!
Now we shall see!
What?! The palace is collapsing!
Bella, run away!
Run away, Princess!
The palace will collapse on you!
Princess!
Let me out!
Let me out of this cage!
We are in danger!
Let me out of here!
Princess! There is not a minute
to lose! Let me out!
I know you are not
capable of killing!
You don't really want me to die?!
I won't be the one to kill you,
but you will die buried
under the rubble of this palace!
And then, finally,
I will be the most beautiful,
of this kingdom
and of the whole world!
Come on, mirror!
My magic mirror
is collapsing!
My duty as a mirror
is over. I was already old.
Now that you are no longer the first,
you, of my rhyming verdicts...
...will no longer hear my voice
to know who is the fairest.
Satisfied, I retire
and give the palm to Sapphire.
- Bella!
- I must flee!
Bella, let me out!
Please! Bella!
Save me, Bella! Help me!
Now I want to show you again
what you are going to become.
Oh, no! It is not possible!
Once your springtime fades,
you will take on your true appearance
and this is how you will become,
because indeed within you there is ugliness.
Only on the outside is there beauty.
This identity of yours,
if you do not change, will prevail.
But I want to suggest to you
a remedy, to finish:
if you change your heart inside
and show a little love,
you will return serene and beautiful
and Sapphire, just as she was,
she will become your great friend.
This is, more than words can say,
the beauty of life.
I have finished.
Goodbye, Your Highness.
Bella, be careful!
- Come, quickly!
- Just in time!
Goodbye, Bella.
- Well, Sapphire, I...
- Don't say anything. I understand.
Goodbye!
You are still the most beautiful
I don't care. I have understood
what true beauty is.
This gift will make you
remember my friendship.
How dear you are, Sapphire!
Goodbye, Your Highness!
Let's go!
- Goodbye!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP